<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sophia Mbataru</title>
    <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sophia Mbataru</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Project 1: Conversational AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>The chatbot about diabetes was developed using Natural Language Processing (NLP).
Scraped over 1000 relevant information about diabetes such as symptoms, medications, and nutrition was web scraped from reliable sources.
Used the RASA Framework to build the chatbot and train it using the scraped data.
Implemented Natural Language Understanding (NLU) was to help the chatbot understand the user&amp;rsquo;s intent and respond appropriately.
The chatbot can improve patient care, increase efficiency, and lead to cost savings for patients and healthcare providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Energy production prediction using Time series Models</title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>The project aimed to predict energy production using time series models, which are statistical models used to analyze data over time to make forecasts or predictions.
Collected and analyzed energy production data over time, which was then cleaned and preprocessed to prepare it for modeling.
Preprocessed the data by removing trends i.e., subtracting the rolling mean and decomposition. Autocorrelation analysis was also done to detect the patterns and check for randomness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Machine Learning Prediction of the Titanic Disaster</title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Created a tool that predicted the survival of passengers based on various features such as age, gender, and ticket class using machine learning models.
Cleaned and preprocessed data using methods such as, imputing missing values, encoding categorical features, and scaling numeric features.
Engineered features from the data to model using logistic regression, decision trees, random forests, and support vector machines (SVMs) algorithms.
Optimized the algorithms using GridSearchCV to reach best model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Prediction of Student&#39;s Dropout and Academic Success</title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Implemented Machine learning techniques such as Logistic Regression, Decision trees, Random forest,and K-nearest neighbors (KNN) were used to predict student dropout and academic success in a project.
Preprocessed the data through encoding categorical variables, dropping irrelevant columns, and splitting into training and testing sets.
Conducted Exploratory Data Analysis to determine the relationship between features and the target variable, and scaled the data using min-max scaling.
Evaluated the model performance using accuracy, precision, and recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Prediction of Customer Churn of a Telecommunications Company </title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Sourced and prepared data for analysis with data preparation done to ensure validity, accuracy, completeness, consistency, and uniformity.
Performed feature selection and engineering i.e., label and one-hot encoding, SMOTE, normalization, and train-test splitting with a 0.25 test size and random state of 1.
Employed modelling techniques such as ADA Boost, Random Forest, SVM, Lasso Regression, Naive Bayes, and Logistic Regression, with the Random Forest model performing best with a score of 92%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: Spam Classfication using NLP and Naive Baiyes</title>
      <link>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sophia14324.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Preprocessed the text data to extract relevant features, including word frequencies and document frequency.
Implemented Naive Bayes and Natural Language Processing algorithms to classify the messages as spam or not spam based on these features.
The model achieved high accuracy in identifying spam messages.
The project is useful for email spam filtering and other text classification tasks.
The project demonstrates the effectiveness of machine learning and NLP techniques in addressing real-world problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
